Guide to the Daniel C. (Daniel Cowan) Jackling Papers, 1911-1956
Department of Special Collections
- INVESTMENTS
  - Itinersries, passes, (8025). (Box 43, Folder 9)
- INDIVIDUALS, correspondence with
  - Alexander, H. F., 1946-1952See also Container 2., (9001) (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Aldridge, Walter H., 1926-1954, (9005) (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Albertsen, Mrs. J. T., 1916-1953, (9006) (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Allgoewer, Albert J., 1955(personal employee of D.C.J.), (9007). (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Bruce, J. L., 1915-1947, (9017). (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Bradley, George O., 1920-1952, (9028). (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Bocking, Charles, 1924-1947, (9031). (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Brownell, Francis H., 1933-1954, (9033). (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Brown, W. D., 1935-1940(personal employee of D.C.J.), (9035). (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Buchman, Louis, 1947-1955See also Container 3., (9037) (Box 45, Folder 1-2)
  - Culberson, Mrs. Mary A., 1932-1937, (9055). (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Cates, Louis S., 1947-1956See also Container 3., (9058). (Box 46, Folder 1-3)
  - Cook, Sam, 1928-1952personal employee of D.C.J.)., (9063) (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Chedsey, William R., 1940-1947, (9064). (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Doubleday, George, 1916-1955, (9071). (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Estes, H. H., 1947-1955See also Container 52., (9088). (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Guggenheim, Simon & Sol., 1927-1949Also information on the Bonanza Mines of the Barber Asphalt Corporation., (9114). (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Guggenheim, Harry F., 1916-1939, (9116) (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Guggenheim, Edmond A., 1916 and 1950, (9117) (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Gemmell, Mrs. R. G., 1926-1950, (9122) (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Grant, Heber J., 1938-1945, (9128). (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Hellmuth, G. W., 1916-1944, (9137). (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Hayden, Charles, 1923-1939See also Container 9., (9138). (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Hammond, F. O., 1948-1954, (9153 pt.2). (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Hamlin, H., ( Pony Express), 1942-1956, (9154). (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Jennings, C. F., 1917-1946, (9162). (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Krumb, Henry, 1917-1948, (9176). (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Kelley, C. F., 1929-1955, (9178). (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Kinnear, J. C., 1948-1955See also Container 9., (9179). (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Moffatt, D. D., 1948-1955See also Container 10., (9199 pt.2). (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Maclean, A. J., 1922-1948See also Container 9., (9215). (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Moses, Horace, 1948-1953, (9218). (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Mudd, Harvey S., 1927-1955, (9220). (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - McWhinney, E. S., 1936-1955See also Container 10., (9222). (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Nickerson, C. A., 1922-1941, (9225). (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Parsons, C. C., 1947-1956See also Container 10., (9229). (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Powers, Edith H., 1952-1955, (9240). (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Quinn, Mrs. Annio, 1924-1952, (9241). (Box 50, Folder 2-3)
  - Ritter, C. P., 1933-1943, (9255). (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Smith, Mrs. J. Willis, 1915-1942, (9268). (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Stone, Calen L. and Robert, 1916-1941, (9270). (Box 50, Folder 6)
    Additional Robert Stone letters in Container 11.
  - Swart, W. G., 1922-1954, (9278). (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Stannard, E. T., 1930-1942, (9281). (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Stewart, Thomas, 1930-1941, (9282). (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Tutt, Charles L., 1940, (9293). (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Thomas, John Charles, 1948-1955, (9294). (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Tooker, H. B., 1918-1955See also Container 10., (9297). (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Thomas, Robert W., 1947-1953, (9300). (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Wells, R. E., 1922-1952, (9318). (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Wiggin, Albert H., 1916-1949, (9321). (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Wagner, F. N., 1930-1952, (9327). (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Whelpley, H.G.B., 1939-1955, (9329). (Box 51, Folder 10)
- PERSONAL-MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE
  - Animals, fowl, etc. (purchased as gifts and for personal use), 1924-1955, (11004). (Box 52, Folder 1-2)
  - Automobiles, 1923-1947, (11005). (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Clothing, general, 1925-1955, (11100). (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Bell, James W. & Company, tailors, 1915-1940, (11105). (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - N. Porter, Saddle and Harness Company, 1937-1941also H. H. Estes, Mimbres, New Mexico., (11123) (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - W. B. Place & Company, tanners and manufacturers of leather garments, 1942-1956, (11124). (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Tweeds purchased in Scotland for various members of organization, 1929-1930, (11125). (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Biography, (11010). (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
  - Birthday messages, 1950-1953, (11011 pt.3). (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Cigars and Cigarettes, 1941-1942, (11016). (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Christmas messages sent, 1949-1956, (11017). (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Christmas messages received, 1949-1954, (11017-1). (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Copper Symbol, 1910-1930, (11018). (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - First high voltage electric transmission line. Provo to Mercur, Utah, 1932-1953, (11026). (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Guns. 1931-1955, (11029). (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Horses, 1930-1952, (11034 pt. 2 and 3). (Box 54, Folder 1-2)
  - John Fritz Medal award to D. C. Jackling, 1932-1948, (11040). (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Masonic matters. 1930-1955, (11055). (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Mausoleum, 1949-1956, (11057). (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Railroad retirement and Social Security matters, 1937-1957, (11075). (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Statue of D. C. Jackling (correspondence with N. G. Morgan, Sr. and Ovard Fairbanks, 1952-1956, (11079 pt. 1-3). (Box 55, Folder 3-5)
  - Statue of D. C. Jackling, clippings and photographs. (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Utah National Guard, Commission as Brigatier General, 1955, (11081). (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Turkeys, etc. (Gift, list), 1950-1956, (11085). (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - University of Utah, Honorary Degree of Doctor of Laws, 1942-1952, (11086). (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - University of California, Honorary Degree of Doctor of Laws, 1940, (11087). (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - University of Southern California, Honorary Degree of Doctor of Engineering, 1940-1942, (11088). (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Jewelry and Furs, general, 1928-1955, (11200). (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Jewelry and Furs, Leyson-Pearsall, Salt Lake City, 1905-1948, (11236). (Box 56, Folder 7-8)
  - Household goods assigned to Mrs. Jackling, evaluation of. 1924-1950, (11305). (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Groceries and miscellaneous supplies [sant as gifts with lists of recipients] 1955-1956, (11315 pt. 15). (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Household goods, apartment inventory, 1921.Woodside inventory, 1930. (Box 56, Folder 11-12)
  - Household goods, inventories, 1921-1948, (11320). (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Legal matters [mostly will and legal fees], general, 1924-1955, (11400). (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Legal matters, Weafer vs. Birch, et al. [contains D.C. Jackling statements of historical interest], 1938-1941, (11407). (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Liquors, general, 1932-1955, (11450). (Box 57, Folder 3-4)
    The next five folders regarding liquor inventories were not filed in the organized collection. They have been added here because of their relationship to group 11450.
  - Liquor inventories, 1920-1940's. (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Woodside liquor inventories, 1933-1947. (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - St. Francis Hotel liquor inventories, 1920's(Jackling's private stock). (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Whiskey inventory, 1951-1955. (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Hotel Mark Hopkins liquor inventory, 1924-1934(Jackling's private stock). (Box 58, Folder 2)
    The next eighteen folders were generally unsorted and unidentified as to grouping. They are added here as Mr. Jackling's personal papers.
  - Miscellaneous, 1934-1942(so identified by D.C.J.). (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Medals won by Mr. Jackling; (See also Container 54). (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Clippings of A.I.M.E. meeting in Salt Lake City, Utah, 1940. (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - D.C.Jackling speeches (in manuscript). (Box 58, Folder 6-7)
  - D.C. Jackling Will. (Box 58, Folder 8-12)
  - D. C. Jackling trust, list of exhibits. (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - D. C. Jackling will. (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Woodside estate (See also Containers 60-62). (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Hayden-Stone, financial affairs, 1931. (Box 59, Folder 3-4)
  - Power of attorney. (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Jackling. (deceased - see gift [unk]) (Box 59, Folder 6-7)
  - Office quarters, San Francisco, 1914, (11507). (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Property, Mark Hopkins apartment, 1925-1932, (11721). (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Property, Woodside estate, 1921-1935, (11728). (Box 60, Folder 3-7)
  - Property, Woodside residence, 1937-1951, (11728-1). (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Property, Woodside superintendent's new residence, 1947-1949, (11728-6). (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Property, Woodside superintendent's weekly reports, 1952-1959, (11728-6). (Box 61, Folder 3-5)
  - Property, Woodside organ, 1930-1938, (11728-3). (Box 61, Folder 6-7)
  - Property, Woodside organ, 1938-1956, (11728-3). (Box 62, Folder 1-2)
  - Property maps and blueprints. (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Property. Woodside expenses, 1944-1954. (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Property. Woodside, general [analysis of cost], 1922-1935, (11728-2). (Box 62, Folder 5-6)
  - Property. Woodside general, 1935-1955, (11728-2). (Box 63, Folder 1-2)
  - Property. Woodside syndicate, (11730). (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Relatives. Dr. Herbert W. Allen and family, 1918-1955, (11800). (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Relatives. W. B. Cowen, 1909-1914, (11803). (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Relatives. Mrs. J. T. Cowan, 1915-1921, (11803). (Box 63, Folder 6-7)
  - Relatives. Mrs. J. T. Cowan, 1922-1933, (11803). (Box 64, Folder 1-4)
  - Relatives. Marths N. Cowan and family, 1922-1944, (11803). (Box 65, Folder 1-4)
  - Relatives. Martha N. Cowen and family, 1945-1956, (11803). (Box 66, Folder 1-3)
  - Relatives. Harry M. Dunn, 1911-1957, (11806). (Box 66, Folder 4-5)
  - Relatives. Harry M. Dunn, 1951-1956, (11806 pt.2). (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Relatives. George W. Dunn, 1911-1916, (11807). (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Relatives. Mrs. Telitha Dunn, 1916-1935, (11807). (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Relatives. Mrs. Mary S. Hewitt, 1916-1930., (11810). (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Relatives. Percival Jackling, 1920-1939, (11814 pts. 1-3). (Box 67, Folder 5-7)
  - Relatives. Percival Jackling, 1939-1955, (11814 pts. 4-7). (Box 68, Folder 1-4)
  - Relatives. Mrs. D. C. Jackling, 1925-1953, (11815). (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Relatives. Mary and Harriet Jolliffe, 1935-1950, (11816). (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Relatives. Dr. and Mrs. Herbert Moffitt, 1916-1955See also Container 10., (11819). (Box 69, Folder 3-4)
  - Relatives. Nickles family, 1924-1929, (11822). (Box 69, Folder 5-6)
  - Relatives. Mrs. Rose Noel, 1916-1924, (11823). (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Relatives. Henry F. Wallace (Gertrude Jackling) 1914, (11828). (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Servants, general. 1915-1955, (11850). (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Servants. chauffeurs. 1927-1951, (11851). (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Taxes, withholding, O.A.B. and California unemployment insurance, 1948-1956, (11901). (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Taxes, income, 1926-1943, (11905 pt. 1). (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Taxes, income 1933-1958, (11905). (Box 71, Folder 1-3)
  - Taxes, income, claims pending, 1926-1932. (Box 71, Folder 4)
    The five cartons of income tax papers listed below were in unnumbered manila envelopes. They have been placed here because of their relationship to the numbered files.
  - Income tax returns and related files 1936-1942. (Box 72)
  - Income tax returns, 1939-1941. (Box 73)
  - Income tax returns, 1942-1944. (Box 74)
  - Income tax returns, 1945-1949. (Box 75)
  - Income tax returns, 1950-1955. (Box 76)
  - Excorp liquidation [for tax purposes], 1927-1938. (Box 77, Folder 1-6)
  - Miscellaneous tax papers. (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - D.C. and Virginia Jackling, analysis of investments, May 10, 1939 and Dec. 31, 1940. (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - D.C. Jackling Financial statements, 1938-1944(lacks 1941). (Box 78)
  - D. C. Jackling Financial statements, 1945-1955(lacks 1951). (Box 79)
- PUBLICITY
  - Publicity, general. 1914-1956, (12000). (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Publicity, Big Men and Big Fortunes by Horace Dunbar, (12000). (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Publicity, subscriptions to magazines and books, 1948-1956, (12001). (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Publicity, miscellaneous booklets arranged chronologically. Listing follows. (Box 80, Folder 4-10)
    - a. Historical Sketch of Mining and Smelting in New Mexico.... U.S. Geological Survey, 1910. (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - b. [Chino Copper Company] The Mogollon Mines, 1913. (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - c. Nevada Consolidated Copper Company. parts 1-5. Mining and Scientific Press. March 5, 1921. (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - d. Ten Years of Chino, The Company parts 1-3 of 10. The Financial World. March 7, 1921. (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - e. Ray Cheap - but not over 825.00. The Financial World. March 28, 1921. (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - f. Two expert opinions on Ray stock, The Financial World. April, 1921. (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - a. Nevada Consolidated Copper - Some Secrets, The Financial World. April 11, 1921. (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - b. Nevada, Dark Horse of Coppers. The Financial World. April 18, 1921.
    - c. Story of Kennecott Copper, The Financial World. May 23, 1921., (3 parts).
    - d. After the war copper boom, The Financial World. June 13, 1921.
    - e. The Chino enterprise. Engineering and Mining Journal Press. Nov. 1923, (5 parts).
    - f. Spanish Atmosphere. (about Jackling's Woodside residence), Pacific Coast Architect. n.d.
    - a. New Mexico Chapter, American Mining Congress, Technical Papers, July 1927(about Chino, Nevada Consolidated, etc.). (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - b. Jackling-Pioneer in Copper, Metals, Nov. 1930.
    - c. D. C. Jackling `92,... M.S.M. Alumnus, Dec. 15, 1930.
    - d. Jackling gets Saunders medal, Mining and Metallurgy, Dec. 1930.
    - e. Mr. Jackling receives the John Fritz medal. Mining and Metallurgy, June 1933.
    - f. A great man doubly honored. Employer's Magazine, June 1933.
    - g. Transcript of investigation of a rockslide at Bingham, Utah, 1930.
    - h. Copper - the everlasting metal, by D. C. Jackling. The Mines Magazine, Nov. 1937.
    - i. Red Bonanza. Shell Progress, April, 1938.
    - a. Copperskins and Copper. The Groundhog, [Aug] 1938. (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - b. Mining Utah Copper. The Mines Magazine. Nov. 1937.
    - c. Jackling, a Titan of the Copper World. Compressed Air Magazine, Oct., 1938.
    - d. Leaders of the mining industry, no. 54 Daniel C. Jackling. The Gold Mining Record, Oct., 1938.
    - e. A message to the mining industry. Mining Congress Journal, Sept., 1939.
    - f. Chino Today. Engineering and Mining Journal, Sept., 1939.
    - g. Partial electrification of hauling system at Chino copper mine. Skillings' Mining Review, Dec., 1939.
    - h. Institute members of promise. (biographical) Mining and Metallurgy, May 1940.
    - i. Mercur the cradle of technical advance. Mining and Contracting Review, August 15, 1940.
    - j. Haulage electrification at the Chino pit... Skillings' Mining Review, Aug. 31, 1940.
    - k. Electrification and change in haulage methods at...Chino. November 29, 1940.(typescript)
    - a. Things one remembers. Industrial News Review, May 26, 1941. (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - b. Same reprinted in Organized Labor, June 21, 1941accompanied by D. C. Jackling comments in attached letter.
    - c. Bingham mountain - bulwark of defense. Mining and Contracting Review, Jan., 15, 1942.
    - d. New Mexico is true cradle of Western mining industry. Skillings' Mining Review, Feb. 27, 1943.
    - e. Copper mining and the Utah Copper mine. Electrical Engineering, November, 1943.
    - f. Red metal monster. January, 1947.
    - g. The Achievement of D. C. Jackling. The Argonaut. August 22, 1947.
    - h. Jackling... Skillings' Mining Review, September 13, 1947.
    - i. Electric traction for heavy short haul. Railway Age, September 4, 1948.
    - j. Mobile telephone serves world's largest open pit copper mine in Utah. The Monitor, January-February, 1949.
    - k. The Mining and Contracting Review, February 28, 1949.(Contains statistics on production).
    - l. D. C. Jackling is 80. M.S.M. Alumnus, July-August, 1949.
    - m. Conversation about copper. Fortune, October, 1949.
    - a. Mining and Contracting Review, June, 1950(cover features Utah Copper). (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - b. About a neighbor of yours, April, 1951.(by Konnecott Copper Company).
    - c. The copper mine at Mineral Creek. Excavating Engineer, October, 1951.
    - d. 1953 is 50th anniversary of founding of Utah Copper mine. Skillings' Mining Review, March 21, 1953.
    - e. Daniel C. Jackling comments upon labor situation. The Argonaut, May 22, 1953.
    - f. D. C. Jackling. Mining Engineering, January, 1954.
    - g. Mining and Contracting Review, August, 1954.(Cover and editorial).
    - h. Daniel C. Jackling. Kennescope, August, 1954.
    - i. Daniel Cowan Jackling... The Argonaut, August 20, 1954.
    - j. Daniel Cowan Jackling... M.S.M. Alumnus, September-October, 1954.
    - k. The Daniel Jackling Award. Mining Engineering, April 1955.
    - l. D. C. Jackling - one of the younger giants in the business world. American Magazine, n.d.
    - m. Gold from copper mines. Business n.d.
    - n. Bingham Canyon - Utah. [ Colliers], n.d.
    - o. Chino Copper Company, by John M. Sulley [1915?].
    - 50th anniversary folder of Utah Copper, 1954.Various items. (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper clippings. (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Pamphlets and souvenir booklets. (Box 81, Folder 2)
      - a. What mining means to Utah.
      - b. The story of Utah Copper, 1925.
      - c. Utah and its mineral wealth, 1930.
      - d. The economic dependence of the population of Utah, 1931.
      - e. The story of Utah Copper, 1924, 1926, 1929, 1936, 1937, 1939, 1940, 1950, 1953.
- PERSONAL-MISC. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Exploration, Canadian Oil Synidicate, 1916-1949, (12146). (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Exploration, Copper Canyon Mining Company, 1921-1936, (12225). (Box 81, Folder 4)
- PHOTOGRAPHS -
  - Early views of Bingham. (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - D.C. Jackling statue in Utah's capitol. (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - Mercur, Utah. (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Bingham, Utah. (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Ray, Nevada. (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Jackling's Missouri home. (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Jackling's parents. (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - D. C. Jackling. (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - D. C. Jackling's associates. (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Two printer's plates of D. C. Jackling (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - Photo albums of Ray Consolidated Copper Company (Box 82, Folder 10-11)
  - Photo album of [Bingham]. Disbound, filed as M93/82/12 in photo file (Box 82, Folder 12)
- PRINTED MATTER
  - Alaska Gastineau Mining Company Annual Reports, 1921-1922. (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Alaska Gold Mine Company Annual Reports, 1912-1916, 1919-1920. (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Butte and Superior [Copper] Mining Company Annual Reports, 1912-1935, 1937-1939. (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Butte and Superior [Copper] Mining Company Quarterly Reports, 1914-1916. (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Chino Copper Company Annual Reports, 1910-1920, 1922. (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Chino Copper Company Quarterly Reports, 1911-1916. (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Chino Copper Company, estimate for ore reserves, January, 1921. (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Chino Copper Company, report on the accounts of, for the five months ending 31st May, 1923. (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Chino Copper Company, interim report, May, 1911. (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Chino Copper Company, miscellaneous calcuations and estimates, re: ore reserves, deferred stripping, etc. June, 1923. (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Gila Copper Company, First Annual Report, 1910. (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - Inspiration Consolidated Copper Company, report on the account of, for the five months ending 31 May, 1923. (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - Chino Mines Division, Inception to date data, 1951-1954. (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Kansas City Structural Steel Company, Annual reports, 1949-1960. (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Ray Mines Division, General manager's annual report, 1951. (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Kennecott Copper Corporation, annual reports, 1923-1956. (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Nevada Consolidated Copper Company Annual Reports, 1907-1932. (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Nevada Consolidated Copper Company, Quarterly Reports, 1909-1916. (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Nevada Keystone Mining Company, 1940-1941. (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Ray Consolidated Copper Company, Annual Reports, 1909-1925. (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Ray Consolidated Copper Company, Quarterly Reports, 1911-1916. (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Utah Copper Company, Quarterly Reports, 1908-1916. (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Utah Copper Company, worth calculation as of 1930. (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Utah Copper Company, Annual Reports, 1905-1933. (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Wyoming-Eastern and Allen Oil Companies report on properties. (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Report on Van Arsdale Ferric Sulphate leaching process at Inspiration Copper Company, 1923. (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - History of Mining in Arizona, 1955.Department of Mineral Resources. (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Dollar Steamship Lines Inc., audit of accounts for 6 months ending December 31, 1932. (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Utah Copper Division of Kennecott Copper Corporation, miscellany.
    - Report on operations, 1952. (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Mimeographed report on improvements in mining practice since 1931. (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Report covering mining operations, 1952-54. (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - General Manager's annual report, 1951. (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Department of mills annual report, 1954. (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Refinery - operations data, 1954. (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Financial and operating statements from inception to December 31, 1946. (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Brief history of Bingham and Garfield RR Company, 1939. (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Other Kennecott Copper Corporation miscellany.
    - Neveda Mines Division, summary of operations for 1951. (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - Investment analysis of three copper companies, 1942. (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - Chino Copper Company, Hurley Plant. (Box 89, Folder 11)
    - Ray Consolidated Copper Company, historical data. (Box 89, Folder 12)
    - Nevada Consolidated Copper Corporation - Chino Mines Division, historical data. (Box 89, Folder 13)
    - Phelps Dodge Corporation and Subsidiary Companies, consolidated financial results, 1931-1954. (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - Reverberatory smelting process by E. W. Davis, University of Minnestta Mines Experimental Station, 1929. (Box 89, Folder 15)
- CONTRACTS
  - Nevada Consolidated and American Smelting and Refining Company, 1932. (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Utah Copper Company and American Smelting and Refining Company, 1932. (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Kennecott Copper Company and American Smelting and Refining Company, gold and silver purchase agreement, 1940. (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Kennecott Copper Company and American Smelting and Refining Company, Chino, Steptee and Diversion refinery procedure. (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Kennecott Copper Company and American Smelting and Refining Company, relating to Ray Mines products, 1940. (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - The Log of the Cyprus, Jackling's private rail car, 1909-1920. (Box 90, Folder 6)
- LEDGERS AND ACCOUNTS
  - Virginia Jackling income and investments, 1920's-1950's. (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Jackling trust. Charles Hayden, [1929-1954]. (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - D. C. Jackling general and investment ledger, [1919-1930]. (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - The Utah Copper Enterprise by T. A. Richard, 1919., (oversize) (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Percentage depletion for mines by L. C. Graton. (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Plans of Excorp Yacht. (Box 91, Folder 6)
- LEDGERS AND JOURNALS NOT BOXED
  - Virginia Jackling, journal of trust fund, 1928,and income and investments ledger, 1928-1945. (Volume 92-94)
  - D. C. Jackling indexes to IN-OUT correspondence, June 1, 1922-[1929]. (Volume 95-98)